

(979) 985-1841 http://tx.ag/nivedhanportfolio nivedhan@tamu.edu

I am a UX designer, experienced developer and a student of the Lean Startup Methodology. I love designing products with a focus on customer needs & their stories, bringing out products that are beautiful, functional and most importantly responsive

EXPERIENCE

UX & Product Designer (freelance)

☐ Oct 2016 - Sept 2017

Applied research-based principles to drive the design of products that fully support end-user needs while also achieving the business vision

- Compiled user research and business requirements into product design by merging organizational vision with customer needs, aligning stakeholder needs
- Designed and generated interactive prototypes to illustrate the business model to customers and investors, generating seed funding of over \$100,000
- Prioritized product features and developed roadmap, facilitating strategic growth
- Designed style guides & visual elements based on user research to communicate coherent experience to executive team and users

Co-founder & Product Designer STEM Space

🛱 Feb 2016 - Nov 2016

Led product design for education startup leveraging social media and evaluated using Lean Startup Methodology at Startup Aggieland incubator

- Designed and developed wireframes and high fidelity prototypes based on user research, combining social interactivity with learning outcomes
- Validated value proposition of product by conducting 100 face to face user interviews, developing product strategy and business model

UX Analyst; Systems Engineer Tata Consultancy Services

□ Oct 2010 - May 2015

Worked with project managers, business analysts and architects at an investment banking giant to create user-friendly interfaces and websites for enterprise customers

- Designed and developed website dashboard to monitor daily stock reconciliation for multiple exchanges and regulatory reports, improving productivity by 15%
- Analyzed and compiled user requirements between cross functional business units in Agile development project, reducing deployment time by 10%
- Identified and assessed success metrics & impact and evaluated risks for 6 ongoing projects, quickening adoption of agile process
- Managed project execution and schedules from soliciting user buy-in to functional deployment for migration of a dashboard, procuring savings of over \$200,000

PROJECTS

HCI Research Projects

Annotating Trails (Research Project)

Synthesis of sensemaking via visual history caching during exploratory browsing

- Conceptualized, developed & performed user testing for a functional prototype to determine knowledge retention while browsing Wikipedia
- Designed novel user interaction to enable multidimensional history browsing through nodes as a chrome extension

Comparative Shopping Experience

Reimagining shopping environment to encourage improved purchasing decisions

- Devised, designed & developed exploratory interaction design using pie menu to aid shopping through ethnographic research, improving user decision making by 10%
- Created goals, personas and metrics for researching and testing to identify pain points, deriving task sensemaking data.

EDUCATION

Texas A&M University 🜎 May 2017 GPA: 4.0

M.S. Management Information Systems

Anna University \$\infty May 2010 \quad \text{GPA}: 3.4

B.E. Mechanical Engineering

KEY SKILLS

User Research

Ethnographic research, Card sorting, A/B testing, Lean UX, Persona development, p-value, Statistical analysis

Experience Design

Wireframing (Sketch, AxureRP)

Prototyping (InVision, AxureRP, Marvel, Flinto)

Data Vizualization

Taxonomy & Information Architecture

Development

HTML, CSS, Responsive design, Bootstrap, Javascript, Java, SQL, GIT

Digital Design

Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, Indesign

Other Skills

Agile, Lean, Jira, Confluence, Google Analytics

ACTIVITIES

McFerrin Center for Entrepreneurship

Organizing workshops and hackathons

Coordinating entrepreneurial activities

Startup Aggieland - Accelerator

Accelerator Participant

IGSA - Indian Graduate Student Association

Vice President of Marketing - Design

Bhumi - Education NGO

Mentoring & Teaching underprivileged children in Math & Computers

Aggies Invent - Innovation Competition

Participant and runner-up